GHEORGHE CRACIUN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mobile: 07927769866 <u>GitHub</u>

Address: 142 Gulson Road, CV1

2JF, Coventry, UK

<u>Portfolio</u>

LinkedIn

gheorghecr1997@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

A prospective Computer Science graduate from Coventry University with proven experience in developing software and web applications. Known as a proactive self-starter, quick learner with solid problem-solving skills that is highly interested in Software Development. Able to collaborate with others but also able to work independently to achieve objectives on time and with excellence. Passionate about developing new skills and keeping up to date with current technologies.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Most Experienced with Swift, SwiftUI, Java
- Some Experience with JavaScript,
 Python, Firebase, React, Koa, NodeJS,
 C#
- Beginner with HTML5, CSS, PHP
- Professional experience using Agile methodology and Unit Testing
- Experience with as SQL and NoSQL databases
- Familiarity of XCode, Android Studio, Visual
- Studio and IntelliJ IDEA

OTHER SKILLS

- The ability to analyze complex technical information
- Can analyze, design, and implement database structures
- Detail-oriented
- Excellent problem solver with great decision-making skills
- Effective time management skills and ability to work under pressure

LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- Portuguese Native
- Romanian Native
- Spanish Intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

Email:

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EriccTS Ltd - Birmingham, UK | July 2020 - Present

- In-house software engineering using Angular
- iOS/Android application development & maintenance for a big multi-national retailer
- Java/JavaFX touchscreen desktop application development & maintenance for a big multi-national retailer

CO-FOUNDER & TECH LEAD

BULBUP | July 2020 - Present

- Team leader during the software engineering process
- Participated in the UX & UI design process of the iOS/Android application
- Acquired a support partnership with a Portuguese company

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST

EriccTS Ltd - Birmingham, UK | July 2019- July 2020

- Data analysis in order to help stores to improve energy consumption, leading to a 10% energy saving during a twelve-month period
- Prepared detailed energy reports to be evaluated at the headquarters
- iOS application engineering for a big multi-national retailer using XCode

PROGRAM TECHNICIAN

Pahldata - Lisbon, Portugal | May - July 2015 & January - March 2016

- Repaired and configured communication equipment using C programming language
- Delivered and installed communication equipment
- Participated in teaching sessions about programming routers using C as the programming language

RESTAURANT SUPERVISOR

Days Hotel - Coventry, UK | August 2017 - July 2018

- Trained new and current employees on the use of ICR TOUCH till software
- · Handled customer inquires and complaints about service and food quality
- Improved stock management trough while utilising excellent organisational and problem-solving skills which reduced the restaurant waste

EDUCATION HISTORY

BSC (HONS) COMPUTER SCIENCE

Coventry University - Coventry, UK | September 2017 - May 2021